Syed Hasnain Bukhari

CONTACT

Life Sukhumvit 48, floor 24th. 122 Sukhumvit Rd, Phra Khanong 10110 Bangkok Khlong Toei TH



syedhasnainbukhari01@hotma



(+66) 630789575. (+92) 3017924305



https://www.linkedin.com/in/has bukhari-30494184



https://www.linkedin.com/ in/ hasnain-bukhari-30494184



https://github.com/ Hasnain-Bukhari

EDUCATION

BACHELOR COMPUTER SCIENCE

Digital Logic Design Assembly Language Data Structures **Design Patterns** Web Programming **Compiler Construction** Concurrent and Distributed Systems

SYED HASNAIN BUKHARI

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of rich professional experience of building and delivering highly scalable, enterprise grade software products. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Sciences from the Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Agoda | Dec 2021 - Present

Leading several teams, working on solutions based upon distributed computing to make the e-commerce scene under the global travel space alive

- Working with teams to migrate long-running legacy systems to a newer and a better stack
- Keeping track of the learning abilities of my team so that they can progress in their respective careers and interests
- Having 1:1s to shape up the team culture and align them with essential matters at the

High Performance Computing **Database Design** FAST - NUCES 2006 - 2010 SKILLS Web Development HTML Javascript Software Architecture Design-patterns Distributed systems Scalability Maintainability Software Development Sustainability Portability Scalability Reasonability **Problem Solving** CompetitiveProgramming Abstract **Draft documentation** docsify Github MARP Joplin MermaidJS FormsIO Communication

face-2-face emails

presentations conference

buy-in talks negotiations

layman conversions 1:1s

organization

- Build a mindset and culture of quality first;
 Owning our stuff and converting them to quality artefacts and systems
- Help the organization envision what moving away from legacy could mean and preach the benefits within the team(s)
- Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies; This helps the team give their best following sprints
- Making an effort around organizational values, so it lives within the team and work we do.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Strategic System International | Nov 2019 - Dec 2021 (2 years 1 month)

Provided leadership across the engineering organization for the aspects of hiring, processes, architecture, grooming individuals and solving complex problems

- Introduced a hiring process and its custodianship (aka The Hiring Squad!)
- Enabled the eco-system of documentation keeping and taking tools along with helping the team to use them day-in-day-out
- Conducted 1:1s with team members to keep their inspirations and motivations up
- Helped to bootstrap various products for a quick test with the upcoming consumer markets for the organization
- Been a part of the team and the solution for complex problems like NotificationCenter, Auth provider selection and payment gateway solution
- Created and vocalized a process of hiring interns and turning them into fellow beings
- Led and represented the engineering department of the organization
- Proactively participated in converting an oldschool organization to an organization with agility
- Helped and created career progression for various individuals in the organization
- Proactively involved me with HR to discuss and demystify challenging problems
- Introduced and have been the most potent catalyst in changing our product platform to be the cross-platform product

- Enabled ways to bring in new dimensions to the product evolution, which were held back because of the absence of engineering leadership
- Focus on quality deliverables -- Provided guidance to bring in an appropriate SDLC
- I got involved and got my hands dirty with architecture decisions at various organizational levels

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CureMD | Sep 2017 - Nov 2019 (2 years 2 months)

SEEK is a diverse group of companies that have a unified purpose to help people live more fulfilling and productive working lives and help organisations succeed.

- Contributed to SEEKs overall product & technology strategy and aligned systems with that strategy
- Ensured that systems were fit for purpose, well-architected and followed current SEEK development practices
- Maintained platform health by ensuring that our systems are secure, reliable, resilient and costeffective
- Drove customer focus to ensure that we deliver excellent outcomes for our customers
- Commenced and maintained a high performing team culture that values collaboration, learning and continual improvement
- Acted as an enabler; Grew my team's technical skills and leadership capabilities through coaching and mentoring. This involves having 1:1s with my teammates
- Lead by example, Which required me to get my hands dirty when needed
- Unblocked the team with whatever it took, having complete ownership of maintaining healthy teams
- Celebrated successes and learnt from the failures; propagated the culture through the teams and exemplified it for the rest of the organization
- Paired with the Principal Engineer of the team to understand the climate and the team's problems
- Participated in and retro-ed the core hiring process through a centralized hiring squad

 Helped the org to move fast to the ecosystem of global products; Away from the local products which we have been dealing with for the past 25+ years

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Logix Infinity | Jun 2016 - Sep 2017 (1 year 3 months)

SEEK is a diverse group of companies that have a unified purpose to help people live more fulfilling and productive working lives and help organisations succeed.

- Been the catalyst for transforming the organization
- Performed the duties as the JavaScript coach for the organization
- Advocated for and implemented software best practices
- Have been the communicator for various teams to maintain their health; sometimes preached the organization's values
- Participated as a core in hiring new and experienced talents
- Propagated automation as a culture rather than an option
- Moved legacy code and data to cloud via lift & shift, greenfield and brownfield methodologies
- Performed the duties of deciding and validating sensible defaults for the organization
- Pushed cloud-first approach in the org, living in an environment of Infra ops
- With the help of fellow architects, I invested time in a flourishing framework of single identity throughout SEEK systems; We did this through educating, enabling, and supporting the needful tools for the teams
- Created several SDKs for a single identity solution within Seek with complete automation and tests. Later helped teams adopt them into various systems

AWARDS

IASA IT Architecture Core (ITAC) – CITAF
 Certification | May 2015 | Iasa Global
 Anchors to the beginning of Architect position
 and responsibilities

 Won the GIKI SOFTCOM 08 (Programming Competition) | Apr 2008 | GIKI University Pakistan
 A speed programming competition of national level

LANGUAGES

- Urdu | Native speaker
- English | Fluent

INTERESTS

- Home improvements & engineering
 Plumbing Electric-appliances Civil engineering
- Software based home solutions
 IoT Home-server plex raspberry-pi cups
 saned
- Watching documentaries
 Idiocracy Lord-of-the-rings movies
 documentaries

REFERENCES

Amir is surely missed by his team/peers and I think any company would find great benefit with the addition of Amir to their leadership and technical team. Wish you all the best Amir and hope our paths cross again.

— Heinrich Rust

As a colleague Amir is friendly, personable, has an easy manner and great sense of humour. A clear communicator with a voice for radio, Amir is wise head on young shoulders.

- Paul Fitzgerald